# George Githuma Njogu

**Software Developer** 

## **SUMMARY**

I am a self taught software developer with experience in JavaScript, NodeJs, Python and React. I am currently familiarising myself with Kotlin for Android development, but with a good foundation of computer science principals especially object oriented programming. I am also an AWS certified cloud Practitioner and soon to be Associate Cloud Engineer through The Google Africa Developers Scholarship.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Mozilla**, Nairobi — Independent Data Contractor, Common Voice Swahili

AUGUST 2021 - PRESENT

Collection and validation of Swahili voice data to be used in curating a Swahili open source data set to be available to the public for use in training Natural Language Processing AI models for Swahili to English voice and text translation.

# **Andela**, Nairobi — Google Africa Developer Scholarship Mentor

JUNE 2021 - PRESENT

Learner mentorship in the Google Cloud track of the Google Africa Developer Scholarship (GADS) 2021 program. This includes but is not limited to; daily meetings with learners to gauge their progress in the program, unblock them where they have challenges with the course material and giving an account of the student progress to Andela, one of the education partners in this program.

### **EDUCATION**

# **Azubi Africa**, Nairobi — AWS Cloud Practitioner

SEPTEMBER 2021 - DECEMBER 2021

12 weeks program covering Linux, Python, Database and AWS cloud practitioner skills

# **Andela, Nairobi** — Google Associate Cloud Engineer

JUNE 2021 - DECEMBER 2021

6 months program by Google through Google Africa Developers Scholarship aimed at preparing students to seat and pass the Google P.O. Box 22354 - 00100 Nairobi, Kenya +254 721 308700

george.githuma@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/ georgegithuma/ https://github.com/Gitthuma

https://github.com/Gitthuma

#### **SKILLS**

Javascript

Kotlin

**NodeIs** 

React

Python

Linux

**Cloud Architecture** 

Container Orchestration

Cloud Nattive CI/CD

#### **AWARDS**

Udacity SUSE Scholarship-Cloud Native Application Architecture Nanodegree program 2021

Google Africa Developers Scholarship 2021

#### **LANGUAGES**

English Swahili Associate Cloud Engineer Certification.

# **Udacity, Online** — SUSE Cloud Native Application Architecture

JULY 2021 - DECEMBER 2021

6 months Nano degree program by Udacity and SUSE aimed at preparing students to design, build and deploy cloud native applications using SUSE native cloud technologies.